[Kite] I have a bad feeling.
It's like I'm missing something.
There's a gnawing anxiety
that won't go away.
[opening theme music playing]
[singer singing in Japanese]
[singer singing in English]
A X FATED X AWAKENING
Now they continue their harrowing journey,
and as they head deeper and deeper
into the heart of the NGL,
hoping beyond hope to finally locate
the Chimera Ants' nest
within the Queen's castle,
they are completely unaware
that one of the King's three Royal Guards
is about to awaken.
Oh, my gosh.
They were all split right in half.
It is quite impressive.
By the look of this one,
he was crushed by a rock
or some other hard object.
Surprising, since Baro's the one
with an iron shell.
So this is what Rares are capable of.
Are you getting worried now?
Come on. I have the king of the jungle's
blood flowing in my veins.
It'll take more than a few humans
to scare me.
I was going to have to miss out
on the yummy feast tonight.
These must be
extremely rare humans indeed.
We'll tear them limb from limb,
and then we'll fill up our bellies
with their flesh.
-[Kite] We're being followed.
-[boys gasp]
[Kite] Not from there.
There are quite a few of them.
while attacking from a safe distance.
Don't get too close.
[Killua] Gon and I
didn't even notice they were here.
[wings fluttering loudly]
[Killua] Ah, damn it!
The trees are getting in the way!
I think it's a trap.
[Flutter] Good. Keep up the chase.
Lord Hagya,
everything is going according to plan.
[both chuckle]
Nice work, Flutter. Hmm?
one strike from my fangs
will finish them off.
Yeah, okay,
but something doesn't feel right.
Huh?
[Hina] Well, you ordered Flutter
to chase down the prey
while you hid in the grass to ambush them.
That's pretty lame, don't you think?
That'd be a whole lot cooler, am I right?
You forget that this is how
the king of the jungle hunts
I guess it doesn't matter much either way
as long as I still get to eat the Rares.
[meat squishing]
A Rare, huh? What the hell is that?
I'll explain the details later.
Its number is 4-933.
It was caught and brought in
by Zazan's squad.
4-933?
Sorry. Doesn't ring a bell,
but it's probably been offered
to the Queen already.
Thing is, her appetite has been getting
much more ravenous lately.
She's gonna give birth
to an incredible king.
[Peggy] Is it possible it escaped?
Creatures that have been injected
with our venom
are rendered immobile
for well over a month,
so there's no way it could move freely
in just three short days.
You can't be certain
when it concerns the Rares.
They definitely aren't like
the humans we're familiar with,
and I would have thought that you,
of all people, would be aware of that.
[Pokkle] The antidote I hid in my molar
came in handy,
but I can barely drag myself
across the ground.
Probably best to just lay low here
for the time being.
[Peggy] Would you mind checking once more?
Come on. Cut me a little slack.
I'm already drowning
in a bunch of work as it is.
Didn't you hear what I just said?
The Queen has a huge appetite right now.
Yes, I heard you,
and I am fully aware of that.
[Pig Ant] I don't know anything
about all this "Rare" stuff,
but why are you so obsessed
with this human?
I'd like to ask it some questions.
I see. Then it's true that not everyone
is able to identify this power.
If I can just figure out
how to master this power,
I can become the king,
and I will rule!
-[rumbling]
-[both gasp]
[angelic choir continues]
Wait. What is that?
[squeals excitedly] He's so handsome!
We're heading back right now.
Huh? But the feast…
[growling]
He must have understood
that he was completely outclassed
and backed down calmly and immediately.
So he's more than likely
a squadron leader.
[Leol] My fangs and my claws…
All I had to do was brandish them,
and in a blink of an eye,
I could end a creature's life
and satisfy my hunger.
There was no greater bliss than that.
I learned this at the cost of my life,
but it made me even stronger.
As we are now,
we have no chance of defeating them.
But we've gained a new weapon,
the ability to learn.
We're going to follow them.
[boys gasp]
Their nest must be close to here.
[gasps] What is that?
[Royal Guard]
That was an interesting story.
You mentioned something about gifts?
Do you mind… if I join you?
[whimpering]
[stutters] That's one of the Queen's
elite Royal Guards.
It was a dream,
a brief and foolish one at that.
[chuckles]
[Rammot] They're on
a whole different level.
A predestined status,
one that cannot be altered.
It's okay. Just relax.
Let's go talk over there.
[gasps] Yes, sir!
My power does not exist for my benefit.
It is for me to be of service to them,
as well as the king they serve.
[gasps]
[heart beating]
I have attempted
to study them many times myself,
but little is written about them.
Asking one of them is faster than
flipping through some dusty old books.
That's why you were looking for one of
them in the first place. Isn't that right?
Yes, that was indeed
the cause of our search.
Yes, right here. Let's see.
"New memories are stored
in the hippocampus,
Hmm. Meow I get it.
manipulators,
and lastly, specialists,
for a total of six categories.
Ca… Categories.
are swayed significantly by…
by…
[flesh squishing]
by these…
these two skills.
Meow I see.
[Pokkle] Besides the basics of Nen,
such as Zetsu and Ren,
an individual's abilit…
An individual's abilities
are deeply influenced by his own…
His own idiosyncrasies.
If your subtype and preference
are luckily the same…
[Pokkle] Water divination
is… is the simplest
[Royal Guard] Go ahead, Rammot.
Give it a try.
Yes, sir.
[Rammot] An enhancer?
[Peggy] More importantly, it confirms that
Rammot is a Nen user. Isn't that right?
Yes. I did.
I think the impact from its attacks
must have opened up your aura nodes.
That, in turn, released your aura.
It seems that if they're sealed,
your aura can't be released.
[Peggy] I see. In fact, Colt presented
the same theory not long ago,
[both gasp]
[chuckles] The leaf withered away.
[Peggy] Impossible.
One of us was actually born
possessing Nen ability
without having to fight a Rare
to obtain it.
Forgive me, Commander,
but that makes you a specialist, correct?
It means you don't belong
to any of the other categories?
It's Neferpitou.
[both] Yes, sir!
I don't need that anymore.
Go and feed him to the Queen.
[both] Of course.
[humming]
[narrator] Even from birth,
Neferpitou already possessed
incredible power.
This revelation,
while celebrated by the Chimera Ants,
[upbeat music playing]
[Gon] Next time, "Light and Dark".
[Gon imitates alarm beeping] Hey, wake up.
It's already 10:55 in the morning.
[Killua] I'll kill-u-a!
[singer singing in Japanese]